Guide to the Alfred S. Niles and Joseph S. Newell, Airplane Structures Typescript
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Alfred S. Niles and Joseph S. Newell, Airplane Structures typescript
circa 1928
SC1038
Newell, J. S., (Joseph Shipley), 1897-1952.
Niles, Alfred S., (Alfred Salem), 1894-
0.25 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were the gift of Walter Vincenti, 1985.
Information about Access
Access: Materials are open to research use.
Biographical/Historical note
Alfred S. Niles was professor of aeronautic engineering at Stanford University from 1927 until his retirement in 1959. In 1929 the first edition of Airplane Structures by Alfred S. Niles and Joseph S. Newell was published by John Wiley & Sons. Newell, who had worked with Niles at McCook Field, was professor of aeronautical structural engineering at M.I.T.
Scope and Contents note
Collection contains corrected typescripts of chapters 1 through 15, list of figures, illustrations, and index. Most of the pages are carbon copies but a few are mimeographed; the illustrations are copies, not originals.
Access Terms
Newell, J. S., (Joseph Shipley), 1897-1952.; Niles, Alfred S., (Alfred Salem), 1894-; Airplanes.
Collection Contents
- Typescript
  - Chapters 1-2 (General Design Procedure; Problems), circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chapters 3-5 (Reactions, Shears, Moments, and Influence Lines; Continuous and Restrained Beams; Design of Simple Beams), circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chapters 6-9 (Torsion; Truss Analysis; Graphical Methods; Design of Simple Ties and Columns), circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chapter 10-12 (Connections; Combined Bending and Compression; Allowable Stresses in Combined Bending and Compression), circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chapter 13 (Deflections), circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chapters 14-15 (Statically Indeterminate Structures; Weight Estimation), circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - List of figures and preface, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Figures, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Index, circa 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)